Hello everyone, welcome back to another lesson with us here at EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的又一堂课。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're going back to school.
今天我们要回到学校。
That's right.
没错。
We're talking about my least favorite subject.
我们要聊我最不喜欢的科目。
That would be math.
那就是数学。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so we're going to be talking about math.
好的，所以我们要讨论数学。
Now I know that many of you, of course, know math.
我知道你们很多人当然都懂数学。
Right.
对。
But do you know the operations in English?
但你们知道用英语怎么说这些运算吗？
Many people find it hard to find the right words to talk about math in English.
很多人觉得用英语谈论数学时很难找到合适的词。
Right.
对。
So that's what we're going to be looking at today.
所以这就是我们今天要讲的内容。
And we'll also look at some names that you can call people who are really, really, really
我们还会看一些可以用来称呼那些非常非常非常
smart.
聪明的人的名字。
So let's listen to our dialogue for the first time and then we'll come back and look at
所以让我们第一次听对话，然后回来再看
those math words.
那些数学词汇。
All right, children, let's review.
好了，孩子们，我们来复习一下。
Tommy, pay attention.
Tommy，注意听。
Sorry, Miss Kadlec.
对不起，Kadlec老师。
Okay, Crystal, now tell me.
好的，Crystal，现在告诉我。
What's four plus 11?
四加十一等于多少？
Um, 15.
嗯，15。
Miss Kadlec always asks Crystal.
Kadlec老师总是问Crystal。
She's such a teacher's pet.
她真是个老师的宠儿。
Okay.
好的。
And what about 56 minus 60?
那56减60呢？
Um, negative four.
嗯，负四。
Very good.
非常好。
12 times 12?
12乘以12？
Very good.
非常好。
Suck up.
马屁精。
144.
144。
Zero divided by one?
零除以一？
Zero.
零。
How did you know that?
你怎么知道的？
Okay, smarty pants.
好吧，聪明鬼。
The square root of two.
二的平方根。
Bet you're not going to get that one.
我打赌你答不上来。
Do it all.
全算出来。
Um, um, 1.4142135.
嗯，嗯，1.4142135。
All right, so that's one smart little girl, huh?
好了，真是个聪明的小女孩，对吧？
Yeah, pretty smart.
是啊，挺聪明的。
Actually, smarter than me in math.
其实在数学上比我还聪明。
All right, so let's take a look at some of those words that the teacher used to ask her
好的，那让我们看看老师用来问她
about certain operations in Language Takeaway.
某些运算的那些词，在“语言要点”里。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay so like we said, you guys know how to do math and you know the words in your language,
好的，就像我们说的，你们知道怎么做数学题，也知道自己语言里的词，
but maybe in English it's a little bit harder to find the right words.
但用英语可能更难找到合适的词。
So let's look at those now.
所以现在来看看这些词。
Okay, so let's look at the first question that she asked.
好的，我们看她问的第一个问题。
What's four plus 11?
四加十一等于多少？
Four plus 11.
四加十一。
Okay, plus.
好的，加。
Plus.
加。
All right.
好的。
So four plus 11, Erica, is?
所以四加十一，Erica，等于？
Uh, let me take a look at here.
呃，让我看看。
Um, 15.
嗯，15。
15.
15。
Okay, so we are adding, right?
好的，所以我们在做加法，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
So that's how you would say.
这就是你要说的。
Let's go with an easy one.
我们举个简单的例子。
Two plus two.
二加二。
Four.
四。
Four, right?
四，对吧？
Or five plus five.
或者五加五。
Ten.
十。
Ten, okay.
十，好的。
You're really testing my skills.
你真是考验我的能力。
So that's how you would add numbers.
所以这就是你加数字的方法。
Now what about taking away numbers?
那减去数字呢？
Okay, so taking away or subtracting.
好的，所以减去或减法。
All right, let's test you again.
好的，再考考你。
In the dialogue, she said 56 minus 60.
在对话里，她说了56减60。
56 minus 60 equals negative four.
56减60等于负四。
Okay, minus.
好的，减。
So that's negative, right?
所以那是负的，对吧？
Minus.
减。
So, and of course, if you have 56 apples and you take away 60, you are left with?
所以，当然，如果你有56个苹果，拿走60个，你还剩？
Negative four.
负四。
Well, actually, you're left with zero apples.
嗯，实际上，你剩零个苹果。
Yeah, exactly.
是啊，没错。
Now, that answer is also interesting, negative four.
那个答案也很有趣，负四。
Negative four.
负四。
That means minus four, right?
意思是减四，对吧？
Four less than zero.
比零少四。
Very good.
非常好。
Negative four.
负四。
Okay, so now for our next operation.
好的，现在看下一个运算。
Twelve times twelve.
12乘以12。
Now, Marco, don't ask me the answer.
现在，Marco，别问我答案。
All right, twelve times twelve equals 144.
好的，12乘以12等于144。
Now that's multiplying.
那是乘法。
Right, or multiplication.
对，或者乘法运算。
Multiplication.
乘法。
Yeah, multiplication.
是的，乘法。
Okay, so this times part, it's very easy to remember because, for example, four times
好的，所以这个“乘以”部分，很容易记住，因为，比如，四乘以
four.
四。
You can just say four, the number four, and you add it, right?
你可以只说四，数字四，然后加它，对吧？
Four times.
四倍。
Four plus four plus four plus four.
四加四加四加四。
Right, so times.
对，所以是乘以。
Times.
乘以。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Now, the opposite of times.
现在，乘法的相反。
All right, the opposite of multiplication is division.
好的，乘法的相反是除法。
Division.
除法。
Okay, so in our dialogue, the teacher said zero divided by one.
好的，所以在我们的对话里，老师说了零除以一。
Zero divided by one.
零除以一。
Any number divided by zero is zero.
任何数除以零都是零。
All right, so let's give another example.
好的，我们再举个例子。
Fifteen divided by three.
15除以三。
All right, so fifteen divided by three equals?
好的，所以15除以三等于？
Five.
五。
Five, exactly.
五，没错。
So divided by.
所以是除以。
Divided by.
除以。
Very good.
非常好。
So after division, the teacher was very impressed, and now she asked a very hard mathematical
所以除法之后，老师非常印象深刻，现在她问了一个非常难的数学
operation, especially for a girl this age.
运算，尤其对这个年龄的女孩来说。
The square root of two.
二的平方根。
The square root of.
平方根。
Square root.
So let's give some examples to show what is the square root.
所以让我们举些例子来说明什么是平方根。
Okay, so if I ask you the square root of nine.
好的，如果我问你九的平方根。
Three.
三。
Three, right?
三，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
What about the square root of four?
那四的平方根呢？
Two.
二。
Two, okay.
二，好的。
So now one more.
现在再来一个。
The square root of sixteen.
16的平方根。
Four.
四。
Okay, so you noticed the pattern, right?
好的，你注意到规律了吧？
And I'm sure everyone knows this in their own language, how you would get a square root.
我相信每个人用自己的语言都知道怎么算平方根。
Exactly.
没错。
So, this language is pretty simple.
所以，这个语言很简单。
You all know it in your own language, but let's hear it again in English one more time
你们用自己的语言都知道，但让我们再用英语听一遍
with the dialogue.
对话。
Alright, children, let's review.
好了，孩子们，我们来复习一下。
Tommy, pay attention.
Tommy，注意听。
Sorry, Miss Kadlec.
对不起，Kadlec老师。
Okay, Crystal, now tell me.
好的，Crystal，现在告诉我。
What's four plus eleven?
四加十一等于多少？
Um, fifteen.
嗯，15。
Miss Kadlec always asks Crystal.
Kadlec老师总是问Crystal。
She's such a teacher's pet.
她真是个老师的宠儿。
Okay, and what about fifty-six minus sixty?
好的，那56减60呢？
Um, negative four.
嗯，负四。
Very good.
非常好。
Twelve times twelve?
12乘以12？
Very good, suck up.
非常好，马屁精。
One forty-four.
144。
Zero divided by one?
零除以一？
Zero.
零。
How did you know that?
你怎么知道的？
Okay smarty pants, the square root of two.
好吧聪明鬼，二的平方根。
Bet you're not going to get that one, do it all.
我打赌你答不上来，全算出来。
Um, um, one point four, one four, two one three five.
嗯，嗯，一点四一四二一三五。
Okay, so we understand the mathematical operations that we saw here, very easy.
好的，我们理解了这里看到的数学运算，非常简单。
But now there was another little kid in there who was very, I think, envious or jealous.
但那里还有另一个小孩，我觉得，很嫉妒或眼红。
Yeah, Tommy.
是啊，Tommy。
Tommy, right?
Tommy，对吧？
So he called her a couple of different names.
所以他给她起了几个不同的外号。
Well let's look at those now in Fluency Builder.
那我们现在在“流利度训练”里看看这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Okay, so the first one that he called Crystal, the little girl, he called her a teacher's
好的，他叫Crystal，那个小女孩，的第一个外号是老师的
pet.
宠儿。
Teacher's pet.
老师的宠儿。
So Erica, what exactly is a teacher's pet?
所以Erica，老师的宠儿到底是什么？
It is the favorite student the teacher has in that class.
就是老师班上最喜欢的学生。
Alright, so it's always the student that's helping the teacher.
好的，所以总是那个帮老师的学生。
Yeah, the smartest student.
是啊，最聪明的学生。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
The teacher's pet.
老师的宠儿。
Yeah, and it has a negative meaning in English.
是的，在英语里有负面含义。
Yeah, I wouldn't say that it's a good thing to be the teacher's pet.
是啊，我不会说当老师的宠儿是件好事。
Like the teacher thinks it's good.
老师觉得是好事。
Yeah.
是啊。
But all of the friends and the classmates, they think it's bad.
但所有朋友和同学都觉得不好。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
Teacher's pet.
老师的宠儿。
And similar to teacher's pet is a suck up.
和老师的宠儿类似的是马屁精。
Suck up.
马屁精。
Again, suck up.
再说一遍，马屁精。
What is a suck up?
什么是“马屁精”？
A suck up is a person who tries really, really hard to make the teacher like him.
“马屁精”就是那种特别特别努力让老师喜欢他的人。
Okay, now we can also use it outside of the classroom, right?
好，那这个词在课堂之外也能用，对吧？
Yeah, at work maybe.
对，比如在工作场合。
Okay, there is always at work, there is always one person who's the suck up, right?
好，工作场合总有一个那种拍马屁的人，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
Now again, this has a negative meaning in English.
再说一次，这个词在英语里是贬义的。
Yeah, I guess in the workplace, the rest of your colleagues don't really like that person
对，我想在工作场所，其他同事通常不太喜欢那个人，
who's considered to be the suck up, who's always trying to please the boss.
就是被认为拍马屁、总想讨好老板的人。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好了。
All right, so the teacher calls Crystal a smarty pants.
好，所以老师叫Crystal“聪明鬼”。
Smarty pants.
聪明鬼。
Okay, so this is also a little name calling, right?
好，这也算是一种小绰号，对吧？
So what is a smarty pants?
那什么是“聪明鬼”？
Somebody who is too smart.
就是太聪明的人。
Too smart.
太聪明。
Who tries too hard to be smart.
就是太努力表现聪明的人。
Now this is only for little kids, right?
这通常只用于小孩子，对吧？
I wouldn't call you a smarty pants, right?
我不会叫你聪明鬼，对吧？
No, it's definitely for children.
对，这绝对是针对孩子的。
Adults don't say this.
成年人不会这么说。
Unless maybe you are joking or having fun with someone.
除非你在开玩笑或跟人闹着玩。
Yeah, but if you say it, you are suggesting that you're being like a child.
对，但如果你说了，就暗示你表现得像个孩子。
Right.
对。
Okay, smarty pants.
好，聪明鬼。
And our last one, and this is also a very good phrase and a way to describe someone,
最后一个，这也是一个很好的短语和描述人的方式，
know it all.
“万事通”。
Know it all.
A know it all.
一个万事通。
Sometimes you say Mr. Know it all, right?
有时候你会说“万事通先生”，对吧？
Yeah, that's right.
对，没错。
Okay, so what is a know it all?
好，那什么是“万事通”？
Somebody who tries to show everyone that they know it all.
就是那种试图向所有人展示自己什么都知道的人。
They know everything.
他们什么都知道。
Yeah, they're so smart.
对，他们太聪明了。
They have the answers to everything.
他们什么问题的答案都有。
But they really, really try and show everyone that they know everything.
但他们真的非常努力地向所有人展示自己什么都知道。
These people can be sometimes a little bit irritating, right?
这种人有时候会有点烦人，对吧？
Yeah, very, very annoying.
对，非常非常讨厌。
Annoying.
讨厌。
Yeah.
对。
All right, so it's not a good thing to be a know it all all the time.
好，所以一直当个万事通可不是什么好事。
Yeah, actually all of these phrases are not good things to be.
对，实际上所有这些短语都不是什么好标签。
Okay, so let's listen to our dialogue one more time and then we're going to come back
好，那我们再听一遍对话，然后回来
and Erica's going to tell us how much she hates math.
Erica会告诉我们她有多讨厌数学。
All right children, let's review.
好了，孩子们，我们来复习一下。
Tommy, pay attention.
Tommy，注意听讲。
Sorry, Miss Catlett.
对不起，Catlett老师。
Okay, Crystal, now tell me.
好，Crystal，现在告诉我。
What's four plus eleven?
四加十一等于多少？
Fifteen.
十五。
Miss Catlett always asks Crystal.
Catlett老师总是问Crystal。
She's such a teacher's pet.
她真是个老师的宠儿。
Okay, and what about 56 minus 60?
好，那56减60呢？
Negative four.
负四。
Very good.
非常好。
Twelve times twelve?
十二乘以十二？
Very good, suck up.
非常好，马屁精。
144.
144。
Zero divided by one?
零除以一？
Zero.
零。
How did you know that?
你怎么知道的？
Okay, smarty pants.
好，聪明鬼。
The square root of two.
二的平方根。
Bet you're not going to get that one, know it all.
我打赌你算不出来，万事通。
1.4142135.
1.4142135。
All right, so Erica, you were telling me that you hated math or you still do.
好，Erica，你刚才说你讨厌数学，或者现在还讨厌。
Well, yes, that's true.
嗯，是的，没错。
I really do hate math and even doing a simple, you know, like 16 plus 32 is too hard for
我真的讨厌数学，就连简单的，比如16加32，对我来说都太难了。
me.
So you were never really that type of person that's good with numbers.
所以你从来就不是那种擅长数字的人。
No, I'm terrible with numbers.
不，我对数字一窍不通。
I can't even remember my own phone number.
我连自己的电话号码都记不住。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
对。
Like I really, if someone asks me for my phone number, I have to look on my phone in the
比如如果有人问我的电话号码，我得在手机通讯录里找。
address book to find it.
Well, yeah, sometimes numbers can be difficult.
嗯，是啊，有时候数字确实很难。
I kind of liked math when I was younger.
我小时候还挺喜欢数学的。
It just made sense.
它很有逻辑。
Well, I guess there's a reason why I'm an English teacher and not a math teacher.
嗯，我想这就是为什么我是英语老师而不是数学老师。
And I was actually not very good at language.
而实际上我语言方面并不擅长。
But here you are.
但你现在在这儿。
Exactly.
没错。
Well, I mean, in Spanish, I like grammar.
嗯，我是说，在西班牙语里，我喜欢语法。
Not very good at that, all those rules.
不太擅长，那些规则太多了。
Yeah, but you're pretty good at English.
对，但你英语挺不错的。
Oh, that's all right.
哦，还行吧。
That's all right.
还行。
Yeah.
对。
What about you guys?
你们呢？
Tell us what your favorite subject or your least favorite subject in school was.
告诉我们你在学校最喜欢或最不喜欢的科目是什么。
What about you?
你呢？
Do you have any favorite subject or did you have a favorite subject?
你有没有最喜欢的科目，或者曾经有最喜欢的科目？
History.
历史。
Yeah.
对。
Okay.
好。
I liked chemistry for a while.
我有一段时间喜欢化学。
Oh, God.
哦，天哪。
Chemistry involves numbers.
化学涉及数字。
Well, a little bit, but it was interesting as well.
嗯，有一点，但也挺有趣的。
So come to the website, everyone, EnglishPod.com and you can find lots of other resources there.
所以大家来访问网站EnglishPod.com，那里有很多其他资源。
And also be sure to check out our activity stream where you can answer and ask very quick
也请务必查看我们的活动流，在那里你可以根据你的水平快速回答和提问。
questions depending on your level.
So you can choose if you're an elementary student, then you would be talking to other
所以你可以选择如果你是初级学生，那么你会和其他初级学生交流。
elementaries.
That's right.
没错。
Thanks for downloading this lesson and until next time, goodbye.
感谢下载这节课，下次再见，拜拜。